Nethra Mugala

nethra.af68@gmail.com | (937) 516 2193 | Miami, FL 33126

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nethra-65b58485/ https://nethraui.github.io/myportfolio.github.io/



SUMMARY

Experienced in object-oriented programming, developing, testing, debugging code and designing interfaces. Developed web applications from scratch using Dojo framework and RESTful APIs. Capable of learning quick and master new technologies. Strong troubleshooting and problem-solving skills with an analytical mindset.

EDUCATION

Wright State University - Fairborn, OH

2016 - 2018

Master's: Computer Engineering

G. Narayanamma Institute of Technology and Science, INDIA

2012 - 2016

Bachelor's: Electronics and Communication Engineering

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, RESTful Web services, J2EE, JAX-RS, Microservices, Spring, Bootstrap,

Dojo, React.

Programming Languages: Java, C, C++, Python.

Databases: Oracle, IBM DB2, MySQL, MongoDB, Server, Firebase Database.

Version Controls: Bitbucket, SourceTree, Git

Applications/Tools: IBM Rational Application Developer (RAD), Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, IntelliJ, WebSphere, IBM Http server,

Tomcat, Postman, SQL Developer, JIRA, Jenkins, UCD, Confluence

WORK HISTORY

Software Developer | NextEra Energy - Miami, FL

May 2019 - Current

- Improved user experience measured by an increase in customer satisfaction by 25% by developing web application using HTML, CSS, JavaScript with Dojo framework.
- Built **RESTful APIs using Java** to export the data to external application.
- Implemented webpage migration from Struts to Dojo framework to make it work on multiple devices, saved development time by separating server-side and client-side coding and *optimized the page reload time by 50%*.
- Developed new application from scratch on cloud using *Spring framework*.
- Launched 3 new features into production in a span of 2 months. Managed milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- Developed reusable components to use across projects which reduced rework for developers by 15%.
- Consulted with Product Manager to identify minimal viable product and decomposed feature set into small scoped user stories.

Software Developer Intern | Tres Mercari Group, India

March 2016 – July 2016

- Developed company's page using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript and used jQuery, AJAX via JSON to request data and update the HTML page.
- Oversaw all the stages of Software Development Life Cycle including quality assurance and integration testing.
- Learned software engineering process improvements and best practices.

CERTIFICATIONS

• AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

PROJECTS

Weather Application

Designed a prototype for weather application in Adobe XD for every screen size and then Developed a Responsive Weather application using ReactJS in Visual Studio Code. Used Weather API to get weather information and used fetch () method to get the data from the API. For UI design, Flexbox layout is used, and Bootstrap dependency is installed through npm.

Technologies used: Adobe XD, HTML5, CSS3, ReactJS, Bootstrap, npm, Weather API, Google Fonts, Visual Studio Code

Android Application

Course Project for Distributed Computing

Lead a team of 5 and developed an android application, which is designed to connect a tourist and a guide at a tourist place and then charge for the tour duration at the end of the session. I built Login and Register pages and stored credentials in Firebase Database. *Technologies used:* HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Android Studio, Firebase, Google Maps API